Hello, I am Berend Gort from the company Nearby
Computing. I'm from the Department of AI Research, and
today I will be presenting to you a demo about the Cognitive Framework
where we use this framework to deploy some state-of-
the-art time series forecasters. A time series forecaster
is when you send it, for example, some CPU data,
and then it returns some predictions.
This is all deployed as a microservice, and
this is a part of the Verge Work Package 5 Deliverable
2.2, the Edge for AI platform. So,
what is the Cognitive Framework? Here we have a scenario where we
have a prediction setup with the Cognitive Framework used.
As for me, I'm a machine learning engineer, but I could be working in
parallel to data scientists and deep learning engineers or other colleagues
interested in uploading models and serving models.
It's possible through the CogFlow library to then, through
your coding, upload a model into the Cognitive Framework,
which then uploads that to a tracking server.
From the tracking server, experimental results are saved
and recorded to a PostgreSQL database.
Also, at the same time, the artifacts like the model weights
are stored to an S3 bucket.
If you want a server model, you can also
do that with the CogFlow library, where
you can identify an experiment by looking at the experiment
values and then pull a model from the S3 storage.
The Cognitive Framework packages the model and then deploys
it in any particular manner the user wants.
So now we will log into the environment, and here
we arrive in the HIRO overview edge
micro datacenters, where we have home with all quick shortcuts.
Some notebooks, work areas, run experiments,
experiments with KFP pipelines,
like pipeline runs and maybe some recurring runs,
also volumes, tensorboards for data analytics,
and an MLflow section. And now we will
go to the notebooks, and here we find our work environment
which is called the notebook code, and we will start
the server. Now the notebook has started, and we can connect to
it. Now we will shortly go over the code.
All of this other redundant code is the model,
and the experiment, the input data, and some utility
functions. Here you can see the attention, decoder, embedder,
encoder, but that's not very significant. What's significant is
this file, run_cogflow_server. As you can see, it imports
CogFlow as CF, and if we ctrl-F CF throughout the
document, we use the CogFlow library
internally throughout this experiment to log the
experiment, to set the experiment name, to start the run, to log some
hyperparameters of this model, to log some metrics.
Let's see what else. And, of course, to finally
infer the model signature, which means that we later on know
how to send inference requests to the model and to
log the model into the
Cognitive Framework.
Then we have some exception, and then
we have a couple of pipeline functions, and
in order to show that, I'll first go to the end, and here is the
complete pipeline. Basically, it exists. This is the CogFlow pipeline
called Informer Pipeline, where we integrate the Informer time series forecasting
pipeline. Step one: Preprocess data cleaning,
data downloading, data conversion. Step two: Training task
where we input the output of the preprocessed
task and finally use the train task
to serve the model into an inference
microservice. We create a CogFlow client and then run
the full pipeline. Before, in the code, these
individual larger functions are defined, and I will not go into
them. Simply, to run this, we go Python 3,
run_cogflow_server.py, Enter, then
we go back to the interface, we can take a look at runs
where now our Informer Pipeline has appeared
and we can take a look at the pipeline. The individual
microservices for each function are being
spun up and executed. In a later stage we will see the
successful execution of the pipeline. As you can see the individual
steps, preprocessing, training and serving, all executed in
sequence. And this means now we have an Informer living
in this environment which is ready to
serve some inference, for example some API
request about some resource usage of some containers
or Edge or Fog servers.
That will be all. Thank you, I hope you enjoyed the demo.